迈克 · 诺斯: 所以我们在这里要处理的最后一件事就是什么时候使用泛型。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So the last thing we're
gonna tackle here is when to use generics.
这是一个非常非常强大的想法。
It's a really, really powerful idea.
但是人们遇到麻烦的类型开始爆炸的复杂性,
But people who run into trouble with types
that begin to explode in complexity,
通常是因为过分热衷于使用泛型。
often that comes from
overzealous use of generics.
我也会仔细阅读博客文章。
And I would also be careful
reading Blog articles.
并且质疑你在那里看到的信息。
And question the information
that you see out there.
因为这是很多内容都会出错的一件事。
Because this is one thing that
a lot of content gets wrong.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我想给你们看一个不好的例子。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: I wanna show
you a bad example here.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我们有一个叫做“形状”的界面。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So
we've got an interface called shape.
它上面有一个叫 draw 的方法。
It has a method on it called draw.
圆形从形状上延伸，圆有一个半径。
Circle extends from shape,
circle has a radius.
所以在这里，我们说画出形状。
So here, we're saying draw shapes.
我们有一个类型参数，其中 s 必须扩展形状。
And we have a type parameter
where S must extend shape.
我们接受一个 s 的数组，然后遍历每个数组并绘制。
And we take in an array of S's, and
we iterate over each of those and draw.
这里是另一个只使用基类的实现。
Here is another implementation
that just uses a base class here.
所以泛型非常适用于两件事。
So generics are great for
relating two things.
我取一个 t 的数组，然后给你们一个 t 的字典。
I take in an array of t, and
I give you back a dictionary of t.
泛型，即类型参数，是将这两者联系在一起的东西。
The generic, that type parameter,
is what ties those two together.
你给我线，我给你线，对不对？
You give me strings,
I give you back strings, right?
在这里，我们只使用这个类型参数一次。
Here, we're only using
this type parameter once.
而且您总是可以消除使用过一次的类型参数。
And you can always eliminate
a type parameter that's used once.
有一种习俗，人们喜欢把它用在,
There's a convention that
people like to use where,
我并不完全反对这个观点。
I don't disagree with it as much.
其中，为了方便起见，他们将对类型断言使用泛型。
Where they'll, for convenience,
use a generic for a type assertion.
例如，它们将包装一个函数和
For example,
they'll wrap fetch in a function and
允许您传递指示响应结构的类型参数。
allow you to pass a type parameter
indicating the structure of the response.
好吧，我的意思是，你完全可以排除它，对吗？
Okay, I mean,
you could certainly eliminate it, right?
但其中也有一些便利因素。
But there is some
convenience factor there.
你眼前的这种东西,
This kind of thing that you're
looking at in front of you,
这里一点都不方便。
there's no convenience here.
这只是不必要的抽象。
This is just unnecessary abstraction.
但是这确实告诉我们，它有一个用处。
But what this does show us,
it is useful for one thing.
它确实告诉我们在这里指定这种类型,
It does show us that
specifying this type here,
这样我们就可以进入这个方法的绘图程序。
that's what allows us to
access this method draw.
这样我们就得到了和这个一样的东西。
This gets us the same thing as this.
因此，类型参数上的约束等效于在
So constraints on type parameters
are equivalent to specifying the type on
一个参数，它规定了你在 s 上的函数里能做什么，对吗？
an argument, in that it dictates what you
can do within the function on s, right?
在这两种情况下，我们有点绘制，点绘制，对不对？
In both cases, we've got dot draw,
dot draw, right?
在这里，它来自这里。
Up here, it's coming from this.
在这里，它就是从那里来的。
Down here, it's coming from that.
迈克 · 诺斯: 什么事？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Yes?
演讲者2: 所以在第121行，如果形状不是一个界面
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So on line 121,
if shape was not an interface and
这是一个类型化名，不会工作吗？
it was a type alias, would it not work?
迈克 · 诺斯: 我想会没事的。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: It will be fine, I think.
字体形状等于这个。
Type shape equals this.
没问题。
Yep, no problem.
这是，我们在非常大的重叠的地方
This is the, we're in the very
large amount of overlap where
选择其中一个并没有什么坏处。
there's no real downside to
choosing one of the other.
演讲者2: 当然，好吧，我想我只是不明白为什么在121行,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Sure, well, I guess I'm
just confused on why on line 121,
如果你以形状传递，它们有半径，这不是错误吗？
if you're passing in shapes and
they have radius, wouldn't that error?
因为它只是期待只有画的东西。
Because it's just expecting
something with only draw.
迈克 · 诺斯: 你能说清楚为什么你认为它会出错吗
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Can you articulate
why you would expect it to error so
我能回答这个问题吗？
I can answer that question?
演讲者2: 是的，因为这个界面,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Well, yeah,
so because the interface,
某个东西实现了一个接口，但它可能有其他属性。
something implements an interface,
but it could have other attributes.
迈克 · 诺斯: 完全正确 说话人2: 使用类型别名,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Totally.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: With a type alias,
这不是很严格的定义吗？
isn't that like a strict definition?
它必须有这样的东西，如果你通过一个圆圈来绘制形状,
It has to have this stuff, and
if you pass a circle in to draw shapes to,
你只是告诉它我想要一个形状，它不也期望一个半径吗？
and you're only telling it I want a shape,
wouldn't it also expect a radius?
迈克 · 诺斯: 如果我在这里要求圆圈，是的,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: If I was
demanding circle here, yeah,
我会说这是一个过度迈克北: 这是要求
I would say this is an overly
&gt;&gt; Mike North: This is asking for
太多了，因为我不需要这里的半径。
too much,
in that I don't need radius down here.
我现在可以控制半径了。
I have access to radius now.
如果我需要这个，我会要求绕圈。
If I needed this, I would demand circles.
我会说你得给我传圆圈。
I would say you've gotta pass me circles.
我喜欢遵循的规则是，你只要求你需要的东西
The rule I like to follow is you ask for
only what you need and
你把所有东西都还回去。
you return everything you can.
所以你只要求你需要的东西，这样你就可以用这个平方和
So you ask for only what you need so
that you can use this with square and
三角形和二维点，也就是 x 和 y。
triangle and 2D point,
which is just gonna have an X and Y.
如果这能行如果这都取决于绘图函数,
If that's gonna work,
if it's all up to the draw function,
那你就不需要更多的细节了。
then you need no further details.
这是你的最低要求，你可以坚持下去。
This is your minimum requirement,
and you can stick with that.
另一方面,
Now, on the other hand,
如果你要退货，你希望你的消费者
if you're returning something,
you want your consumers to be able to
无论安全程度如何，都能接触到这个物体的丰富内涵。
access all of the richness of this
object to whatever degree is safe.
假设我们有多种类型的集合比如一个列表一个数组,
So let's say we had multiple types of
collections, like a list, an array,
它扩展了 list，一个链表。
which extends list, a linked list.
如果数组和链表上有特殊的方法，则没有理由
If array and linked list have special
methods on them, there's no reason for
我会给你们一个非常低级的基础类。
me to kind of give you back
a very low level base class.
这会阻止你安全地访问到达
That would prevent you from
safely accessing to reach
下面的功能。
functionality underneath.
所以只要求你所需要的，尽你所能归还一切。
So ask for only what you need,
return everything you can.
- 什么事，先生?-那么
Yes, sir?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So
这两个函数是等价的，对吗？
the two functions are equivalent, then?
但是你是说最好的那种只是普通的杀伤力太大了？
But you're saying the top one
is just overkill on the generic?
迈克 · 诺斯: 它们是等价的，而且它们编译起来也完全一样
&gt;&gt; Mike North: They're equivalent, and
they will compile to exactly the same
除了函数的名字之外。
thing, aside from
the name of the function.
演讲者3: 你能举个例子说明你实际上想在哪里做-吗
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Could you give an example
where you would actually want to do the-
迈克 · 诺斯: 当然，这个怎么样？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Absolutely, how about this?
迈克 · 诺斯: 让我想一想。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Let me think for a moment.
有必要使用类型参数的示例？
An example where the type
parameter would be necessary?
扬声器3: 你实际上想在通用语上使用它。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Where you'd actually
want to use it on the generic.
迈克 · 诺斯: 好的，我们开始吧。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Yeah, okay, here we go.
迈克 · 诺斯: 所以我得找点别的事做。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So
I'd have to involve something else.
对不起，不是这样的。
Sorry, that's not true.
迈克 · 诺斯: 那是布尔值。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: That's Boolean.
我必须引入这个类型参数的第二个用法。
I'd have to introduce a second
use of this type parameter.
例如，返回这些东西的一个数组。
For example,
return an array of these things.
我会说地图
And I'd say map, and
迈克 · 诺斯: s 是真实的。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: S is drawn true.
报税表。
Return s.
迈克 · 诺斯: 那么现在，让我们来看看，为什么这个不开心？
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So now,
let's see, why is this unhappy?
[听不见]迈克 · 诺斯: 谢谢。
&gt;&gt; [INAUDIBLE]
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Thank you.
迈克 · 诺斯: 好的，现在，事实上我在两个地方使用这个,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Okay, so now, the fact
that I'm using this in two places,
这是有目的的。
this serves a purpose.
没有这个，即使我只是说它返回形状,
Without this, even if I just
were to say it return shape,
我们有一个明显的缺点。
we have a significant downside.
在这里，如果我试着说 drawShapes1并传递一个圆形数组。
In that, if I were to try to say
drawShapes1 and pass an array of circles.
迈克 · 诺斯: 这就是我的圈子。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: There is my circle.
你不喜欢那里的什么？
What don't you like there?
半径是一个数字。
Radius is a number.
迈克 · 诺斯: 我必须明确地说明这一点。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: I'd have to
be explicit about this.
它已经在说这是一个形状上的未知属性。
It already is saying this is
an unknown property on shape.
我可以在外面创建这个。
I could create this outside.
迈克 · 诺斯: 现在，它会很高兴的。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And now, it'll be happy.
但是现在，如果我想把它锁起来,
But now, I'm in a situation where
if I wanted to chain off of that,
我已经把它简化为一系列的形状。
I have reduced this down
to an array of shapes.
我已经没有圆形数组了。
I don't have an array of circles anymore.
我没有拿出我经过的东西,
I didn't get out what I passed in,
我得到了函数需要的最低公共值。
I got out the lowest common
thing that the function needed.
然而，如果我们返回 s 的数组，现在 radius 就存在了。
Whereas if we return an array of s's,
now radius is present.
演讲者3: 如果我们绕圈子通过，你会得到圈子回来。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: If we pass in circles,
you're gonna get circles back.
我们通过正方形，我们得到正方形回来。
We pass in squares,
we get the squares back.
迈克 · 诺斯: 你可以在工具顶端看到它。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: And
you can see it right in the tool tip.
看到所有的 s 都变成了圆圈了吗？
See how all of the s's
have changed to circle?
这个呼叫站点已经填写了空白。
The blank has been filled
in at this call site.
这就是 type 参数可以给你带来的东西。
And this is where type parameter
would get you something.
在这种情况下，drawShapes 并不关心形状的细节。
In that drawShapes does not care
about the particulars of the shape.
但是它能做的就是把你过去的东西还给你。
But what it will do is give
you back what you passed in.
麦克 · 诺斯: 或者我也可以回一个承诺，结成 s 或什么的。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: Or I could return a promise
that resolves to s or something.
但关键是，我已经介绍了 type 参数的第二个用法。
But the key is, I've introduced
a second use of the type parameter.
这就使得这个普通的东西是值得的。
And that makes this generic worthwhile.
现在，type 参数正在描述参数和返回值之间的关系。
Now, the type parameter is describing a
relationship between arguments and return.
对于类，你可以说我在构造函数中加入了这个,
And for like classes, you could say
I take in this in my constructor,
这个方法返回这个类型。
and that method returns this type.
这个课程有更多的机会，因为你有这样的机会
There are many more opportunities
with this classes because you have so
对他们来说有很多不同的部分，对吗？
many different parts to them, right?
但是你必须能够指向两个。
But you gotta be able to point to two.
如果你做不到,
If you can't do that,
你可能只是使用了一个类型参数作为某种断言，对吗？
you may just be using a type parameter
as sort of an assertion, right?
或者你是说把它当绳子还给我。
Or you're saying give this
back to me as a string.
把它作为数组还给我。
Give this back to me as an array.
这不是一回事。
That's not the same thing.
这通常不是类型参数的用途。
That's not what type parameters
are typically used for.